<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Investments | The Mentoring Machine]]></title>
  <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/categories/investments/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-31T21:25:24-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ken Yu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Down Year Is an Up Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/31/a-down-year-is-an-up-year/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-31T21:01:20-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/31/a-down-year-is-an-up-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The end of 2015. What a great year of trading, and a great year of learning. I&rsquo;m proud to say all accounts are in the green! I look forward to carrying these skills forward and continuing to sell that premium.</p>

<p>2016, here I come.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands in Pockets]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/29/hands-in-pockets/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-29T14:58:52-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/29/hands-in-pockets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I honestly did not even place a new trade. My hands were in my pockets the entire time.</p>

<p>An exit order did fill, it was for the DIA IC, exited at 50% of max profit. Good. These GTC orders are getting filled effortlessly.</p>

<p>Was today a profitable day? No. Did I feel good about my trades? Yes, because I did not place any. I&rsquo;ve already sold some OOM calls on this overbought stochastic reading, and, because I&rsquo;m not going to add more negative deltas, I&rsquo;m just going to sit and wait for the next drop. At that point, I&rsquo;ll probably lower my delta exposure. For now, not much I can do anyway. I won&rsquo;t even sell puts to flatten those deltas because it&rsquo;s not worth it in a low IV environment.</p>

<p>My honest opinion? Today&rsquo;s rally was the <a href="http://www.zerohedge.com/news/2015-12-29/herd-heading-cliff" title="idiots' rally">idiots' rally</a> of the week. Just saying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking Flight]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/28/taking-flight/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-28T19:54:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/28/taking-flight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I started my first day at Stellar. I would say I made decent progress so far - I thought it would take me a bit longer to get the codebase up and running, but I already have the environment setup and am already beginning to take a look at the code that I&rsquo;ll be working with. Score. Tomorrow, I&rsquo;ll dive deeper into the code, and will be recording what I find in a doc.</p>

<p>On the health side, today was an &ldquo;off day,&rdquo; meaning no working out. For about the first month, no cardio with be incorporated into my fitness routines. This is just for me to retain the new behavioral changes more easily. Tomorrow, I&rsquo;ll be waking up early to hit the gym, so I&rsquo;ll need to review my plan later tonight and mentally prepare as well. As for tonight, I&rsquo;ll be eating the food I had cooked yesterday.</p>

<p>On the investments front, not much happened today. I opened up an IC today on IWM, since it currently showed the highest IV rank out of the DIA, QQQ, IWM, and SPY. A trade was closed in P for a 50% profit, so I&rsquo;ll take that. Other than that, no opening trades today, which is nice. On a low volume day, and not much IV increase, I&rsquo;ll sit on my hands. We&rsquo;ll see how the market behaves tomorrow, but I do not expect volume to pick up either, nor any major market movement to occur, so I&rsquo;ll probably be sitting on my hands again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toxic Trading Assumptions (and Antidotes)]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/26/toxic-trading-assumptions-and-antidotes/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-26T18:18:41-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/26/toxic-trading-assumptions-and-antidotes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are a list of toxic trading assumptions, and ways to rethink the assumption as antidotes to improve my emotions:</p>

<blockquote><p>A Good Day is a Winning Day</p></blockquote>

<p>I should not determine a day as good/bad based on my P/L. A good day is one where I follow my trading rules, from execution to management. I should not be expecting to make profits every day. I should not expect to be happy if I have a profitable day, nor should I expect to be sad if I do not have a profitable day.</p>

<blockquote><p>Success Means Making a Living from Trading</p></blockquote>

<p>It&rsquo;s ridiculous to assume this. People who are experts in other areas spend years becoming such. For example, a doctor spends at least 8 years in school before becoming an expert. Similarly, actors spend years (probably starting from a young age) before they&rsquo;re able to perform. It&rsquo;s more realistic to expect to keep my losses at a minimum and improve my trading process. Expecting to make a living from trading right off the bat will lead me to frustration and failure.</p>

<p><strong>So what are my expectations for my development over time?</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>To enter trades on pullbacks, and <em>wait</em> if necessary.</li>
<li>To sell premium when IV is high (above 50%)</li>
<li>To enter contrarian trades based off overbought/oversold stochastic indicators, and support/resistance levels</li>
<li>To not trade biotechs and FANG naked</li>
<li>To sell iron condors that collect about 1/3 the width of the strikes</li>
</ul>


<p>These are all challenging, but realistic and attainable. Success if measured by achieving these expectations consistently (and not jumping the gun because I feel like I will be missing out).</p>

<p>These will be on the investments page as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/25/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-25T22:09:12-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/25/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello world,</p>

<p>This is the beginning of the blog, which will pertain to the following 3 aspects of my life:</p>

<ul>
<li>career</li>
<li>health</li>
<li>investments</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ll be coaching myself daily to improve upon these areas. Follow along with my blog to view my progress.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
