<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Investments | The Mentoring Machine]]></title>
  <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/categories/investments/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-21T22:50:53-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ken Yu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reviewing and Adding Investment Goals]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/21/reviewing-and-adding-investment-goals/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-21T22:13:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/21/reviewing-and-adding-investment-goals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot of weekly puts are expiring this week for me. That&rsquo;ll bring in a ton of theta, but one thing I&rsquo;ve been trying to do is to stay small. Any violent move to the upside or downside can dramatically wipe my account of profits gained from the previous week(s). With such a clean track record for the year so far, it&rsquo;ll be quite disappointing to see this happen.</p>

<p>Although the ST, when the market is sold so much like what we&rsquo;ve seen, we usually see a spike in volume, followed by a rally the following days. Interestingly, not that much volume traded today. This causes me to be a little doubtful of a rally tomorrow.</p>

<p>One of the things that I really like about ST is that they do directional plays, and they are really good at them. I&rsquo;ve never seen someone to accurate with their trades, so one of the goals that I have currently is to follow some of their trades. I heard a good advice today that will help me pull the trigger, and that is, simply do the trade, but put on a small size. Worry about size later, but focus on staying small and following the entries and exits according to plan. So instead of an outright buying/selling of 1 /ES contract, maybe trade 250 shares of the SPY. Also, perhaps try paper-trading the XEL-CMS pairs trade. For some of their trade ideas, they have unlimited risk on jumbotrons, which isn&rsquo;t my style. I can reduce risk by making the trade a limited risk and perhaps paying a slight debit for the trade.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll update the investments page to include these goals, and as the days go by next week, I&rsquo;ll track my progress on achieving these goals.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Staying Small]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/16/staying-small/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-16T12:49:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/16/staying-small</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The past week has been a huge tidal wave for my equity curve.</p>

<p>I got emotional after finding out that my OOM naked puts on /ES were getting closer to being ITM, sold an /ES to neutralize some deltas, only to find that the market would rip higher the next day. Then I neutralized more deltas by selling more puts (putting on more size), only to see the market drop huge the next day, forcing me to sell another /ES to neutralize more deltas, only to see the market close above my cost basis for /ES.</p>

<p>Obviously, the problem wasn&rsquo;t in neutralizing deltas. It was putting on too much size at the beginning. Instead of starting with many naked puts on the /ES (many as in more than I was comfortable with), I should&rsquo;ve kept it small, and probably should&rsquo;ve bought a more OOM put to reduce risk and lower buying power requirement.</p>

<p>It seems that I still have not learned. The goal of staying small has not yet been achieved. I will mark this as a top goal to achieve in my current investments goal page. I will keep this in check every day, before I place a trade.</p>

<p>Good luck to me next week. I should be good to the downside, and any upside will really bring in some premium.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Outlook on AMZN]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/16/outlook-on-amzn/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-16T12:04:24-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/16/outlook-on-amzn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s a long term look on AMZN:</p>

<p><a href="/images/investments/2016-01-16_amzn_long_term.png"><img src="/images/investments/2016-01-16_amzn_long_term.png" alt="AMZN - Long Term" /></a></p>

<p>Since 2009, AMZN has climbed a long way. Regardless of how ridiculous this is, we can&rsquo;t fight price action - it is what it is. But we can look for opportunities.</p>

<p>Notice the first Fibonacci levels drawn from the 2009 lows to the current highs, and also notice the second Fib levels drawn from the 2014 lows to the current highs. You&rsquo;ll notice that these levels coincide at around 435 (both the 38% from the first Fib and the 61.8% from the second). We can use Fib confluence to help guide us as to where price may trade over the next few months.</p>

<p>From this chart, it appears that 435 is a possible target level. If the market continues to be bearish, and we break below the rough ascending expanding cone pattern shown by the yellow trendlines, expect 435 to come into play.</p>

<p>Other possible downside support levels include the 50% Fib level (of the second fib retracement drawn), followed by the 400.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a closer look at the recent price action in AMZN over the past year:</p>

<p><a href="/images/investments/2016-01-16_amzn_short_term.png"><img src="/images/investments/2016-01-16_amzn_short_term.png" alt="AMZN - Long Term" /></a></p>

<p>In the shorter time frame (next couple of weeks), keep a close eye on AMZN as we may see a bounce. Current market stochastics signal an oversold condition (although we&rsquo;ve been oversold since last week). If we do bounce, and we bounce hard, look for a break above 580 (resistance level from the previous quarter). A break above 580 will cause some short-covering. First target should be 595 (support level of the recent quarter), followed by 630 (intermediate support/resistance level of recent quarter).</p>

<p>Do note that AMZN reports earnings on 1/28 after the market closes. If you plan on avoiding big binary events, stay on options that expire before then.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Been a While]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/16/its-been-a-while/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-16T00:24:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/16/its-been-a-while</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a while since my last post, but it has also been a great start to 2016. I&rsquo;ll give brief updates here on each of the pillars, and more in detail with each deserving their own post.</p>

<p><strong>Health</strong></p>

<p>I was able to prepare meals to take to work most of the time, with the occasional cheat meal. I&rsquo;ve noticed that my body fat has gone down just by look and feel. This is good, and I should press the advantage and use this to push me foward instead of giving me more rope for slack. I need to stock up on lean meats again. I did a great job finishing them all.</p>

<p>In terms of my workouts, I seem to be plateauing in some exercises. Will revisit in specific blog post.</p>

<p><strong>Investments</strong></p>

<p>So far, I&rsquo;m up on the year, but I could&rsquo;ve been more positive on the year had it not been for the past two days of havoc. I overtraded and cost myself some premium I could&rsquo;ve collected. Now, I&rsquo;ll need to wait god knows how long for premium to come in. Besides that, there better be some kind of a downmove, because I&rsquo;m currently short some /ES futures, and any big rips to the upside will kill me directionally unless I sell premium from put options into it. More plans to come, and new goals to try to add to the list to tackle.</p>

<p><strong>Career</strong></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been great so far. The team is friendly, and everyone gets along just fine. I&rsquo;ll be ramping up the Swift portion of our app. Many of the fundamental building blocks is already done. Soon, after the core features are built, I can begin to expand and lead.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Catching E. Coli]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/04/catching-e-coli/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-04T22:45:30-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/04/catching-e-coli</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ok I probably shouldn&rsquo;t have titled the post this way. Anyway, let&rsquo;s take a look at CMG.</p>

<p><a href="/images/investments/2016-01-04_cmg_weekly.png"><img src="/images/investments/2016-01-04_cmg_weekly.png" alt="Catching E. Coli" /></a></p>

<p>Over the past 3 months, CMG has fallen around 40%. Stochastics are screaming the oversold signal (though CMG can still fall further). Note the ascending trendline support going back to 2009. This has acted as a solid support since then, and we can attempt to play CMG for a bounce at around the 400 level.</p>

<p>For those that like to front-run the trade though, you may also target the 433 level, as that is a 61.8% Fib level, with the retracement starting from 2012 lows.</p>

<p>In general, according to technical patterns, it is highly probable that the area from 400 to 433 will act as some level of support or consolidation area.</p>

<p>With the increase in volatility, we can look to the options market to place a trade in hopes for a bounce, as the premium in CMG is slightly inflated.</p>

<p>Please examine the following trade idea:</p>

<p><a href="/images/investments/2016-01-04_cmg_weekly_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/investments/2016-01-04_cmg_weekly_risk_graph.png" alt="Potential trade idea" /></a></p>

<p>Here, we buy 1 400 PUT while financing that by selling 2 375 PUTs, for a total of 0.36 credit. Our breakeven for this trade is around 349. If CMG trades above this price by the 5th Friday of January, we are profitable. This trade has a 99.72% probability of profit, has a maximum loss of $34,964, and a potential maximum profit of $2536.00. For those that do not like the big downside risk, you can also buy a more OOM put, and potentially pay 0 for this trade.</p>

<p>Do note that CMG reports earnings on Feb 2, so to lessen the likelihood of being run over by a binary event, aim to trade options that expire before that date (unless you do want to play the earnings).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
