<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Investments | The Mentoring Machine]]></title>
  <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/categories/investments/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-04T22:36:34-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ken Yu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome the 2016 Stock Market]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/04/welcome-the-2016-stock-market/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-04T22:33:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/04/welcome-the-2016-stock-market</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we finally got some exciting action in the markets. Way to start off the new year</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve gotten used to the idea of selling premium on big volatility spikes, but now, it&rsquo;s time to take it a step further. Instead of selling ICs, sell strangles first, and then, when volatility drops, buy the outer wings for really cheap. That&rsquo;s the next step. Wish I had done that, but it&rsquo;s ok. I still improved from last year by selling at least some premium (I would&rsquo;ve been scared to before). I&rsquo;ll add this goal to the investments page.</p>

<p>What was good:</p>

<ul>
<li>sold premium despite the bearishness</li>
</ul>


<p>What to improve on:</p>

<ul>
<li>should sell strangles, not ICs, on indices when IV is high (Can sell ICs on individual stocks), then buy the outer wings for very cheap when IV crushes to morph strangle into IC</li>
</ul>


<p>Keep a close eye here on this section of the blog. I will try to be posting daily premarket updates.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2016 First Week Overview]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/02/2016-first-week-overview/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-02T18:02:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/02/2016-first-week-overview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time to start packing meals for work.</p>

<p>One thing I want to do for my investments is to follow ShadowTrader&rsquo;s trade ideas more. I&rsquo;ll place a smaller size of them, so that when they do work out, well, at least I&rsquo;m not missing out.</p>

<p>Bulk prep tomorrow. Let&rsquo;s do this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Down Year Is an Up Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/31/a-down-year-is-an-up-year/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-31T21:01:20-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/31/a-down-year-is-an-up-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The end of 2015. What a great year of trading, and a great year of learning. I&rsquo;m proud to say all accounts are in the green! I look forward to carrying these skills forward and continuing to sell that premium.</p>

<p>2016, here I come.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands in Pockets]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/29/hands-in-pockets/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-29T14:58:52-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/29/hands-in-pockets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I honestly did not even place a new trade. My hands were in my pockets the entire time.</p>

<p>An exit order did fill, it was for the DIA IC, exited at 50% of max profit. Good. These GTC orders are getting filled effortlessly.</p>

<p>Was today a profitable day? No. Did I feel good about my trades? Yes, because I did not place any. I&rsquo;ve already sold some OOM calls on this overbought stochastic reading, and, because I&rsquo;m not going to add more negative deltas, I&rsquo;m just going to sit and wait for the next drop. At that point, I&rsquo;ll probably lower my delta exposure. For now, not much I can do anyway. I won&rsquo;t even sell puts to flatten those deltas because it&rsquo;s not worth it in a low IV environment.</p>

<p>My honest opinion? Today&rsquo;s rally was the <a href="http://www.zerohedge.com/news/2015-12-29/herd-heading-cliff" title="idiots' rally">idiots' rally</a> of the week. Just saying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking Flight]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/28/taking-flight/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-28T19:54:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/28/taking-flight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I started my first day at Stellar. I would say I made decent progress so far - I thought it would take me a bit longer to get the codebase up and running, but I already have the environment setup and am already beginning to take a look at the code that I&rsquo;ll be working with. Score. Tomorrow, I&rsquo;ll dive deeper into the code, and will be recording what I find in a doc.</p>

<p>On the health side, today was an &ldquo;off day,&rdquo; meaning no working out. For about the first month, no cardio with be incorporated into my fitness routines. This is just for me to retain the new behavioral changes more easily. Tomorrow, I&rsquo;ll be waking up early to hit the gym, so I&rsquo;ll need to review my plan later tonight and mentally prepare as well. As for tonight, I&rsquo;ll be eating the food I had cooked yesterday.</p>

<p>On the investments front, not much happened today. I opened up an IC today on IWM, since it currently showed the highest IV rank out of the DIA, QQQ, IWM, and SPY. A trade was closed in P for a 50% profit, so I&rsquo;ll take that. Other than that, no opening trades today, which is nice. On a low volume day, and not much IV increase, I&rsquo;ll sit on my hands. We&rsquo;ll see how the market behaves tomorrow, but I do not expect volume to pick up either, nor any major market movement to occur, so I&rsquo;ll probably be sitting on my hands again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
