<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Investments | The Mentoring Machine]]></title>
  <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/categories/investments/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-16T00:33:30-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ken Yu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Been a While]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/16/its-been-a-while/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-16T00:24:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/16/its-been-a-while</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a while since my last post, but it has also been a great start to 2016. I&rsquo;ll give brief updates here on each of the pillars, and more in detail with each deserving their own post.</p>

<p><strong>Health</strong></p>

<p>I was able to prepare meals to take to work most of the time, with the occasional cheat meal. I&rsquo;ve noticed that my body fat has gone down just by look and feel. This is good, and I should press the advantage and keep going, instead of giving me more rope for slack. I need to stock up on lean meats again. I did a great job finishing them all.</p>

<p>In terms of my workouts, I seem to be plateauing in some exercises. Will revisit in specific blog post.</p>

<p><strong>Investments</strong></p>

<p>So far, I&rsquo;m up on the year, but I could&rsquo;ve been more positive on the year had it not been for the past two days of havoc. I overtraded and cost myself some premium I could&rsquo;ve collected. Now, I&rsquo;ll need to wait god knows how long for premium to come in. Besides that, there better be some kind of a downmove, because I&rsquo;m currently short some /ES futures, and any big rips to the upside will kill me directionally unless I sell premium from put options into it. More plans to come, and new goals to try to add to the list to tackle.</p>

<p><strong>Career</strong></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been great so far. The team is friendly, and everyone gets along just fine. I&rsquo;ll be ramping up the Swift portion of our app. Many of the fundamental building blocks is already done. Soon, after the core features are built, I can begin to expand and lead.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Catching E. Coli]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/04/catching-e-coli/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-04T22:45:30-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/04/catching-e-coli</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ok I probably shouldn&rsquo;t have titled the post this way. Anyway, let&rsquo;s take a look at CMG.</p>

<p><a href="/images/investments/2016-01-04_cmg_weekly.png"><img src="/images/investments/2016-01-04_cmg_weekly.png" alt="Catching E. Coli" /></a></p>

<p>Over the past 3 months, CMG has fallen around 40%. Stochastics are screaming the oversold signal (though CMG can still fall further). Note the ascending trendline support going back to 2009. This has acted as a solid support since then, and we can attempt to play CMG for a bounce at around the 400 level.</p>

<p>For those that like to front-run the trade though, you may also target the 433 level, as that is a 61.8% Fib level, with the retracement starting from 2012 lows.</p>

<p>In general, according to technical patterns, it is highly probable that the area from 400 to 433 will act as some level of support or consolidation area.</p>

<p>With the increase in volatility, we can look to the options market to place a trade in hopes for a bounce, as the premium in CMG is slightly inflated.</p>

<p>Please examine the following trade idea:</p>

<p><a href="/images/investments/2016-01-04_cmg_weekly_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/investments/2016-01-04_cmg_weekly_risk_graph.png" alt="Potential trade idea" /></a></p>

<p>Here, we buy 1 400 PUT while financing that by selling 2 375 PUTs, for a total of 0.36 credit. Our breakeven for this trade is around 349. If CMG trades above this price by the 5th Friday of January, we are profitable. This trade has a 99.72% probability of profit, has a maximum loss of $34,964, and a potential maximum profit of $2536.00. For those that do not like the big downside risk, you can also buy a more OOM put, and potentially pay 0 for this trade.</p>

<p>Do note that CMG reports earnings on Feb 2, so to lessen the likelihood of being run over by a binary event, aim to trade options that expire before that date (unless you do want to play the earnings).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome the 2016 Stock Market]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/04/welcome-the-2016-stock-market/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-04T22:33:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/04/welcome-the-2016-stock-market</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we finally got some exciting action in the markets. Way to start off the new year</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve gotten used to the idea of selling premium on big volatility spikes, but now, it&rsquo;s time to take it a step further. Instead of selling ICs, sell strangles first, and then, when volatility drops, buy the outer wings for really cheap. That&rsquo;s the next step. Wish I had done that, but it&rsquo;s ok. I still improved from last year by selling at least some premium (I would&rsquo;ve been scared to before). I&rsquo;ll add this goal to the investments page.</p>

<p>What was good:</p>

<ul>
<li>sold premium despite the bearishness</li>
</ul>


<p>What to improve on:</p>

<ul>
<li>should sell strangles, not ICs, on indices when IV is high (Can sell ICs on individual stocks), then buy the outer wings for very cheap when IV crushes to morph strangle into IC</li>
</ul>


<p>Keep a close eye here on this section of the blog. I will try to be posting daily premarket updates.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2016 First Week Overview]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/02/2016-first-week-overview/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-02T18:02:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/02/2016-first-week-overview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time to start packing meals for work.</p>

<p>One thing I want to do for my investments is to follow ShadowTrader&rsquo;s trade ideas more. I&rsquo;ll place a smaller size of them, so that when they do work out, well, at least I&rsquo;m not missing out.</p>

<p>Bulk prep tomorrow. Let&rsquo;s do this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Down Year Is an Up Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/31/a-down-year-is-an-up-year/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-31T21:01:20-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/31/a-down-year-is-an-up-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The end of 2015. What a great year of trading, and a great year of learning. I&rsquo;m proud to say all accounts are in the green! I look forward to carrying these skills forward and continuing to sell that premium.</p>

<p>2016, here I come.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
