<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Career | The Mentoring Machine]]></title>
  <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/categories/career/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-21T22:50:53-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ken Yu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Been a While]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/16/its-been-a-while/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-16T00:24:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2016/01/16/its-been-a-while</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a while since my last post, but it has also been a great start to 2016. I&rsquo;ll give brief updates here on each of the pillars, and more in detail with each deserving their own post.</p>

<p><strong>Health</strong></p>

<p>I was able to prepare meals to take to work most of the time, with the occasional cheat meal. I&rsquo;ve noticed that my body fat has gone down just by look and feel. This is good, and I should press the advantage and use this to push me foward instead of giving me more rope for slack. I need to stock up on lean meats again. I did a great job finishing them all.</p>

<p>In terms of my workouts, I seem to be plateauing in some exercises. Will revisit in specific blog post.</p>

<p><strong>Investments</strong></p>

<p>So far, I&rsquo;m up on the year, but I could&rsquo;ve been more positive on the year had it not been for the past two days of havoc. I overtraded and cost myself some premium I could&rsquo;ve collected. Now, I&rsquo;ll need to wait god knows how long for premium to come in. Besides that, there better be some kind of a downmove, because I&rsquo;m currently short some /ES futures, and any big rips to the upside will kill me directionally unless I sell premium from put options into it. More plans to come, and new goals to try to add to the list to tackle.</p>

<p><strong>Career</strong></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been great so far. The team is friendly, and everyone gets along just fine. I&rsquo;ll be ramping up the Swift portion of our app. Many of the fundamental building blocks is already done. Soon, after the core features are built, I can begin to expand and lead.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking Flight]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/28/taking-flight/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-28T19:54:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/28/taking-flight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I started my first day at Stellar. I would say I made decent progress so far - I thought it would take me a bit longer to get the codebase up and running, but I already have the environment setup and am already beginning to take a look at the code that I&rsquo;ll be working with. Score. Tomorrow, I&rsquo;ll dive deeper into the code, and will be recording what I find in a doc.</p>

<p>On the health side, today was an &ldquo;off day,&rdquo; meaning no working out. For about the first month, no cardio with be incorporated into my fitness routines. This is just for me to retain the new behavioral changes more easily. Tomorrow, I&rsquo;ll be waking up early to hit the gym, so I&rsquo;ll need to review my plan later tonight and mentally prepare as well. As for tonight, I&rsquo;ll be eating the food I had cooked yesterday.</p>

<p>On the investments front, not much happened today. I opened up an IC today on IWM, since it currently showed the highest IV rank out of the DIA, QQQ, IWM, and SPY. A trade was closed in P for a 50% profit, so I&rsquo;ll take that. Other than that, no opening trades today, which is nice. On a low volume day, and not much IV increase, I&rsquo;ll sit on my hands. We&rsquo;ll see how the market behaves tomorrow, but I do not expect volume to pick up either, nor any major market movement to occur, so I&rsquo;ll probably be sitting on my hands again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Next Play]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/25/second-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-25T22:47:17-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/25/second-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Starting Monday, December 28, I&rsquo;ll be starting a new chapter in my career. I&rsquo;ll be taking on the role of leading the iOS team over at <a href="http://www.stellar.aero" title="Stellar Labs">Stellar Labs</a>, helping them create their mobile product. I&rsquo;m super excited for this opportunity, am looking for a change of pace in terms of my work and my career growth, and cannot wait to just crush it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/25/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-25T22:09:12-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mentoringmachine.com/blog/2015/12/25/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello world,</p>

<p>This is the beginning of the blog, which will pertain to the following 3 aspects of my life:</p>

<ul>
<li>career</li>
<li>health</li>
<li>investments</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ll be coaching myself daily to improve upon these areas. Follow along with my blog to view my progress.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
